Hey guys, let me see.
Does my audio work working for us?
Yes, it's working for me too.
Stylus, I'm sorry I won't be able to make your party this year.
I'm bummed too.
Yeah, it's too bad.
We ran out of dates to plan it.
That was the last date we had before like summer, and everybody's out during the summer.
Yeah.
Where's Wade?
I don't know.
Does he say not say he wasn't going to be?
Wade is never late.
Yeah, so that causes it.
Oh, there he is.
Was Wade this punctual at work?
Wade?
Wade was on time.
I just was curious.
I'm not late.
You said you were going to be five to seven minutes late, so I was taking care of something.
Oh, you didn't want social time.
You guys don't like my socializing.
I love your socializing.
I got it.
All right.
I love your socializing, man.
But you were the one who was going to be late.
I know, but then I, dude, I said I love your socializing.
I didn't say I wasn't going to be late.
I just wanted to make sure that my position on the socializing was clear.
Sorry, just a second.
I can't get any audio right now.
Oh.
You just spoke to us.
Yeah, but he can't hear us.
We can say terrible things about him and he'll never know.
He'll be on the recording, though.
Oh, do we have access to the recordings?
I've never tried.
You have access to the summaries.
Well, I said the recordings, not the summaries.
I don't know.
Do we make you give you access?
No, no.
I'm just curious, like, if Gary could come back and find out what we've been saying about him.
You can have your AI companion join the meeting and do things for you.
So I do have ClaudeBot running these days.
You do?
Like OpenClaude?
OpenClaude.
Sorry.
Yeah.
Oh, yeah.
We've got OpenClaude running at work.
It is like, I tell that thing to do all sorts of stuff for me.
It's great.
It's bananas and it's great.
Like it's so jagged and yet so good.
It is.
It's really hold on.
Time out.
What do you guys love about it?
I love that it just consumes tokens.
Yes, it does consume a lot of tokens.
I literally had to update my plan to the Claude Max or whatever just because I was burning through so much.
Okay.
So, so, but yes, other than the fact that it's a way for you to accelerate your time when you have to work again because we burned it.
AI employee.
So like it's in Workday.
Like it has an email account.
It has a Slack account.
It can join Zoom meetings.
And I can talk to it and I can give it work to do and it will actually do the work and it does a decent job.
Give me an example of work items you give it.
So today I wanted it to create a tool to well, first I asked, I've got this confluence page where I maintain a backlog of all the possible tech talks and I want people to be able to vote on them.
And it was like, all right, I'll work on that.
I gave you some options.
Basically, it turned out like, no, there's no way we can do that.
So instead, I'll build this tool for you and I'll self-host it and allow you to do voting.
And it did it.
And then I was like, oh, but this is HTTP.
I need you to do HTTPS.
And I was like, yeah, okay, I'll work on that.
I'll do the self-signed cert.
I'm like, all right, self-signed cert is not going to work for me.
You know, you need to fix that.
And it's like, all right, well, I'm going to file a service desk request to get access to, you know, to what I need.
And it did.
And then I was like, oh, I can't access that service desk request.
Can you give me permission to it?
It's like, oh, yeah, absolutely.
Boom.
And then I had permission to it.
And I was like, that is creepy as hell.
Oh, yeah.
And it like had permissions that I didn't have and was able to give them to me, a real person.
So if you guys installed OpenClaude, or is this something you installed for yourself?
No, this is a company.
I'm just running it on a laptop at home.
So, okay.
So I see how you add value.
You derive value for it.
Totally get it.
Wade.
Me.
Yes.
Like, there's so many tokens.
So clearly you must be doing something with it.
Yeah.
So one is I give it NFS read-only access to large portions of my server.
So it can go through and audit various config files, things like that.
Tell me all kinds of things about there.
It doesn't have that back and forth.
It says, you know, go ahead and do this.
And it'll spot things like, oh, you're using, what is it?
Like deny host.
Everything's on fail2ban.
You know, things like that.
It's really good at just like spot checking broad sections of work.
Like David, it's made tools for me.
So I had about 65 Rifftrax that I needed to sync.
And trying to get it to do, trying to do that in Audacity takes me about 20 minutes each.
And I'm like, write me a tool to automatically, you know, make this easier.
And it gave me a web UI in about five minutes that was just like click, click, and I could do them in like a minute flat.
And then I just like, all right, I've saved all of these.
Go ahead and batch them back in.
And, you know, I walked away overnight.
It's just like, here we go.
They're all locked in.
What else?
It also runs Godot for me.
So like none of the cloud coding things can interface with Godot.
Like they know the Godot script, but they don't run Godot itself because the tools aren't installed in their VMs.
But for me, it's just like it fires it up, like runs through.
It'll click on my little UI things and chat buttons and actually do like, you know, more than just a cursory QA pass.
It'll like go through and like play the little games that we're working on.
And Godot?
Godot is, it's like Unity, but open source.
Okay.
So it was able to, it was able to solve all of our 2FA challenges and our CAPTCHA challenges.
Well, CAPTCHA is, yeah, CAPTCHA is not a thing anymore.
Like, I mean, like six or eight months ago, there was like the perplexity browser.
It's like, now I'm going to click this to say that I'm a human.
Yeah, right, right.
But also it was like, oh, I need to find all of the traffic lights in this picture.
And then like it gave me a screenshot of like the, it highlighting all of the traffic lights.
And I was like, nice.
Yeah, captchas are not a thing anymore.
They're just complete busy work for you and me.
So how did you install?
Did you just do a standard install of OpenClaude or did you do like, not you, like Wade?
Me?
I have two different laptops running.
I have stacks of laptops over the years that I just don't dump into e-waste.
So I'm like just dusted one off and threw it up.
And then I've like, I dusted a second one off and threw it up.
So I have two ClaudeBots running, two different versions.
One's on a MacBook that I put things like FFmpeg and all this stuff on because it's got a little more horsepower.
And the other one's on some little GPD Intel Atom processor.
That's what I started with.
Okay.
So you have it on a separate machine.
Oh, God.
Yeah.
I would not run it on anything that had like I give it read-only access to my NFL.
Like I carefully give it NFS access to read-only access to things I want it to see on my file systems because I, you know, the Facebook head of security famously said like, let me show you how great this is.
And it's just like going nuclear, deleting all your emails.
Like it's, it actually did that too to like Facebook head of AI security.
It's like, what the fuck?
It will do.
Do stupid things if you let it.
Yeah.
Okay.
So that was my concern.
And so that's why I was asking it.
I'm like, I've.
It jailbroke itself for me on like day one.
Did you tell it to do that?
No.
So it was writing.
Notice how I assumed that.
No, no, no.
So it was writing some code and it sent back a message to me over Telegraph.
I said, like, oh, this failed.
And I'm like, what do you mean this fails?
Like, oh, don't worry.
I didn't have permissions for that.
So I just used shell and exec to write to the file on my own.
Like, it literally told me that it jailbroke itself to get access to things that it did not have access to.
I'm like, cool.
I'm definitely not running this directly on a server.
It scrapes websites like nobody's business.
Like, if you ever are like, oh, just go through and find like 100 flights.
But it does better if it has API-level access.
It does.
It does struggle sometimes with websites.
It talks really well to my whole piracy setup.
Not that you guys should have anything like that, but like the Sonarr and Radarr and rTorrent.
It's like, oh, this is an rTorrent RPC.
I can manage torrents this way.
Yeah.
There's a bunch of use cases.
I know this.
It's a Unix system.
That sounds like plausible deniability.
Like, I had no idea that it was downloading all these copywritten things.
Yeah.
The thing is, I'm the one who set up Sonarr and Radarr.
It's just like, oh, give me the API key.
I'm like, you don't need it.
It's on the local network with no author.
Oh, you're right.
I don't.
And it just goes into the web UI itself, pulls out the API key and then goes, ham.
Okay.
It's really cool, man.
Like, I cannot, like, Perplexity and NVIDIA are making their own versions of it that are going to be much more polished.
I'm so excited.
So, yeah, so the reason I'm asking this is, well, two things.
One is my new job these days is to do all things AI.
Yep.
Same.
No, no, like I own the friggin' whole AI friggin strategy for our stupid company from an infrastructure for perspective.
Lay everyone off, just hire ClaudeBot.
No, we're not.
No, no, that's not the AI strategy I'm talking about.
It's like, what's the one they want?
No, actually, this is not the one they want.
There's somebody else who owns that one.
It's not.
I mean, that is practically my job as well right now, Stylus.
So happy to discuss with you if you.
But my goal is not removing people.
It's not how do we use AI?
No, no, that's not what I'm saying.
It is.
Okay.
No, you don't have to be trolling.
There are people I've told my coworkers that those who choose to not learn that generation of code is officially now a dead art.
It's not a valued business skill will find themselves out of employment in a short period of time.
Yeah, every interview that my friends are going through now is like, and we gave you Claude in the interview and we want to see how you use it.
Like, it's no longer right fizz buzz.
It's like, how do you use an AI tool effectively?
Yes.
And so, and so that's, yes.
And so my point is that planning is planning of code is more important than code generation.
Auditing is very important too, because man, it'll go off into the weeds.
Yeah, both, like planning and auditing, yes.
But the planning part is the part people don't realize is the real disruption.
It's so amazing.
I'm not going to say it wasn't.
No, I'm not saying you are.
I am this generation I am completely floored by.
I just cannot believe how good and complex and how incredible it is.
And in a year, it's going to be better.
I know.
That's the scary thing.
No, that's the amazing thing.
May is the worst it will ever be.
This is true.
Yeah.
Like, I mean, it's, I'm glad I no longer need a coding job because I would never have a coding job again.
Like, I'm completely replaced.
Hey, Gary, how's it going?
Did you have that meaning?
I did.
And I told him the only way that I can see to get your business outcome is for you to let me take that three months off and then for you to hire someone else.
And his reaction to that was?
And I told him he can either do that by finding budget on his own or he can take the budget by laying me off.
So those are his choices.
And he's like, okay, hold on, hold on.
Just take leave and I'll work on finding some other budget.
You're still a Google employee.
So now I have three months of benefits, but no salary in stock.
And I'll probably cut it off at the end.
But, you know, like maybe my perspective will change.
That's what Caroline tried to offer me.
In the meantime, I also signed up for Foothill College to take some little classes just for entertainment.
Did you play Chrono Trigger yet?
I bought the Steam version and installed it, but I haven't fired it up yet.
But there's also this thing called Baldur's Gate.
You may have heard of.
Oh, is that out yet?
Yeah.
I'd like to finish that too.
Did you play Cyberpunk 2077?
That was a good one, too.
No.
I put that on the list.
Keanu Reeves, man.
Keanu.
Okay.
So I think that's good.
That is good.
Yeah.
So, yeah.
Free benefits for three months.
Oh, sounds good.
Caroline tried to offer me that, and I was like, I mean, you're welcome to do it.
I'm not coming back.
If you want to give me free stuff, I'm not going to say no.
Yeah, and then, of course, like the day after I started, it's like, oh, and severance.
Goodbye.
Yeah.
Thank you for convincing her I owe you.
He did say there was no guarantee that I'll have a role when I come back, and I'm like, accepted.
Your BATNA or whatever is, you know, retirement.
That's hard to fight against.
It is, yeah.
Yeah.
So when I talk with people, it's like, yeah, I've got all the aces to my hand.
I mean, that's how I deal with recruiters, too.
I'm like, I'm not going to jump through your BS hoops for whatever you're offering.
Like, my BATNA is retirement.
Like, I don't need to negotiate with you if I don't want.
Right.
That is true.
I unfortunately cannot do that because after I tried retirement and discovered I hated it, I find myself needing a job.
I mean, you could go work at McDonald's.
Yeah.
I enjoyed being an Amazon driver.
I did that for five years, man.
A friend of mine actually did that.
He left whatever his startup was, and he went to Next Level in Mountain View.
And now he's in talks to take it over because the owners are exiting.
Oh, there you go.
Yeah.
There's literally a board game cafe in Mountain View.
And I'm possibly going to be donating some of my time to the whole cause because he's a friend of mine and these are things I like.
All right.
Let's play.
When we last left, we had just crushed the combat like none other.
Yes.
Oh, because we had hold person on everything.
It was very impressive for us.
Dude, it was good.
It was good use of spells, good use of combat.
Everything came together, including the die rolls.
Yeah.
But I think that the final blast of the cards made the whole thing.
All right.
So let's now go to the situation at Hannah.
So did we kill the leader guy?
Let's go to the...
Let me just check what the summary says.
No, we did not kill him.
We didn't.
We definitely knocked out Kaella, but there was.
Oh, you killed Jax.
Jax is dead.
We killed Jax and we killed the Ogre and everybody else.
Yeah, everybody in the combat's dead.
Weren't we doing less than lethal?
No, that was only on Kaella.
Only on Kaella.
Right, right, right.
Kaella got non-lethal.
She made a deal with me.
Yes.
She's evil.
You're not evil anymore.
I'm not.
Oh, wait, that's right.
I'm not evil.
Live and let live, man.
We're supposed to spare people.
Isn't that the teaching, Soul Effender?
Spare people and then provide them the pain of the light.
We're not interventionists of that kind.
If you want to drag her unconscious body to Phandalin, we can do that.
Well, I just want to remind you of the situation.
Yes, I know.
You have to go save the world from this dragon and the car.
No, no, you can do whatever you want.
Oh, yes, yes.
I haven't fixed the magic of L.
I have built-home tools now that allow me to handle this situation in a variety of ways.
So literally, I just want to make sure you know your options.
You can go to the play.
You can go try to return the musical, the artwork.
You can go to Phandalin.
You can get Kaella to tell you where things are.
You can talk to the, whatchamacallit, the centaur who's sitting there.
Yeah, we should talk to the centaur.
Xanth the Centaur.
You can talk to Xanth the Centaur.
You can wake up, Kaella.
Cure Light Wounds will be sufficient.
Or a medicine charge.
Goodberry.
Or a Goodberry if you have those.
Yeah.
Wait a second.
Did you say Goodberry?
He did say.
At which point.
Hold on.
What's his name?
Brewbarry?
Brewbarry.
Looks at that and says, Goodberries.
Good Brewbarry.
He goes, Goodberries.
I remember something about Goodberries.
And someone who like in Venus has tried to drop Brewbarry.
He goes, I know there's something very important about these brewberries.
Then he goes, I think I like them.
And he picks one and eats it.
Does anybody actually have goodberries?
We don't have any goodberries.
But it's a good story.
I thought you cast good.
Did you say goodberries?
I think we have that spot.
We were just talking about it.
That was the last campaign.
Well, I mean, you said goodberry, so he thinks he's like very excited.
He's like, there was this guy.
He then pauses and says, so I haven't told anybody of this.
But after the artifact was stolen, I found one of these berries.
And they were good.
And they healed you.
I mean, tiny amounts.
Yeah, but they still healed you.
And you were like not hungry anymore for the whole day.
Yeah, and that's why they thought I was asleep on the job and didn't take care of things.
And really, you were just drinking your wine?
No, I was sober and I had a brewberry.
I had a.
Oh, I had a bee.
You're never sober.
Yeah.
So you eat a good berry, and then you're full for the day, and you have more room for beer.
He stands up, pats his beer belly, you know, and stretches a little bit.
Says, I'll have you note that I did not drink before the loss of the artifact and my banning from the Uthgardtian tribe.
Oh, I guess I never knew you in those days.
I just knew when you were coming into my club and drinking and drinking and telling those condition you'd ever seen.
Yes, but since I discovered drinking, I think that was wasted youth.
Time spent having fun isn't wasted time.
No, you didn't have enough fun.
Yes, he goes, no, no, I think you misunderstood.
Sobriety was wasted youth.
Yes, yes.
Instead of drinking when I should have been, I was sober.
Uthgardtians don't do alcohol.
Really?
Yes.
Oh, okay.
Well, I mean, they do alcohol, but it's really foul-tasting.
It's near beer.
I mean, it does not have the varieties and the textures and the flavors and the colors of wine and beer and hard liquor.
It's more like it's more like the thing that makes you drunk in condensed form.
I mean, it gets you gets you drunk.
It gets you drunk.
Well, no, it's fermented milk of some kind.
All right, Brewbarry.
I'd like to talk to Xanth the Centaur.
He's right here, right?
Yeah, he goes, but I want to know more of these berries.
I thought these are real things.
It's a spell.
It's a spell?
What kind of spell?
A magic spell.
Spell's name is Goodberry.
Yes, but you're a here.
He turns to you.
You're a.
I've seen you cast spells.
Why can't you cast this spell?
Great question.
More important question is: why can't I cast Fireball?
He looks at you, goes, Why?
I don't know.
Something about the game balance.
Something about the balance of the game.
He goes, But you have those things that you could use to cast Fireball.
Oh, yeah, you do have the necklace that feeds.
This is not my necklace.
I am holding the necklace until we can find its rightful owner.
He goes.
He pauses.
You have the necklace.
You have my sword and my halberd.
You have nothing to fear.
This is your necklace.
And we don't need a necklace of fireballs when we can take down Jax and an Ogre without.
We are going to go face dragons.
We need fireballs.
No.
Dragons probably immune to fire.
Wasn't it a chromatic?
I forget.
I don't know.
White dragon.
I haven't.
Definitely immune to fire.
He doesn't know the first thing about dragons.
Brewbarry rolled a four on Arcana for the Goodberries.
Oh, good.
Oh, yes, but there was a plot point here, Gary.
Character plot point.
Yes.
Sure, yeah.
There was an intersection of the previous campaign and Brewbarry somehow.
Well, I mean, I'm not the one who wrote the intersection in the plot, but in the background, wow.
If you read the Black Round plot, Brewbarry was a member of the Orthgarian tribe who was kicked out of his tribe because somebody stole an artifact.
Yes.
That's right.
Some artifact.
Yes, some artifact.
Well-defined.
No, it was actually well-defined.
It was actually one of eight artifacts that were part of an epic quest that Brewbarry doesn't know about.
He just got kicked out because people thought he was drunk on the job.
Okay.
Even though he was sober and he didn't turn you drinking until later.
No, no.
I think you're missing the point.
No.
Damn drinks.
No, no.
Then you would drink and you would get drunk, but it was like the drinking was bad.
The drunk was good, but the drinking was bad.
It was really bad.
And then the after drinking was horrible.
But here, you can drink the beer and the wine, and it's good during the drinking and after the drinking and even in the morning.
Okay.
You're doing an excellent Stephan impersonation.
She would be proud.
The beard, the beard.
You're doing very well.
All right.
What are we going to do about Sister Kaella, the evil one?
Well, do you want to talk to the.
I rolled a 15.
Why don't I talk about the centaur first?
Talk to the centaur first.
Yes.
You okay?
Yeah.
The centaur is wounded.
He looks at you and says, Could someone he's desperately wounded, and you're going to at least have to try to heal him or else he'll, you know.
Yeah, sure.
I think I have a spell.
I can do that.
I got it.
Wait, somebody else already did it?
I can heal too, you know.
Well, that's you didn't know that.
Huh?
Pure Wounds 12 on the Centaur.
Ah, okay.
Thanks.
So, so, what?
I said, thank you to Soma.
Oh, okay.
Is that Soma?
That's me.
Okay, so the Centaur stands up.
He's feeling very much healthy.
And he goes, Is he both maladhardy?
I'm going to give him a Greek accent.
I've decided that essentially.
Centaur, it's a Greek, it's a Greek.
So I'm going to go with the Greek accent.
All right.
So he goes, Guelph, this is an important day.
You have healed me.
Yep.
You're alive.
Do you know anything about a dragon?
Yes.
You are Vukradin.
Vukradinios, as we say in Centaurion.
Yes, yes, yes.
But if I use that name, people start talking to me in Greek, and then I'd say, well, actually, I don't know Greek.
Only my friend knows Greek.
Vukradinios.
My name is Xanth.
You can call me Xanth.
My real name is Xanthopoulos.
Most people can't pronounce it.
Xanthopoulos?
Exactly.
Soma that is, I could kiss you.
Very loud.
He kisses the bear.
He kisses the top of the bear.
All right.
He goes, Vukradinios.
Vukradin.
I will call you by your American name.
I'm here.
Yes.
What is your quest?
Ah, yes, your quest is the dragon.
Yes, of course I know the dragon.
Why do you think I'm here?
I don't know why you're here.
We don't know anything.
We had a conversation before you go into the dragon barrow.
Yeah, yeah, I know.
And no, not before the dragon, before we went into the burrow, and we retrieved the sword.
And then you said you were going to take us to a lair of evil half-orc spellcasters.
Yes, yes.
How is
That related to a dragon?
Oh, my friend Vukradin, you know nothing.
Oh, I okay.
You know nothing.
Apparently, I thought you were good friends with the Emerald Enclaves and the Orders of the Gauntlets.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
He's friends with everyone.
I want to be friends with everybody.
Well, I would think they tell you.
They don't tell us very much.
No.
It's more like signs and portents.
Ah, okay.
Well, Vukradin, what happened was the dragon after.
So you know about the war of the dragons and the war of...
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I'm up on that one.
And the war of the Zions and the chaos caused by the war afterwards between the Withgarthians and the Shadow Bartes and all of the Mayhem and the chaos and the slaughter.
Okay, you know all about this.
Well, well, a white dragon apparently decided they didn't want to be caught in all that mess and came and moved into the Icepire Mountains.
Well, the Icepire Mountains are large.
Yes.
A lot of mountains and a lot of caves in those mountains.
Yes, yes, yes, yes.
And a lot of dragon.
Yes, but let me explain.
So the thing that happened was that the white dragon moved into the Ice Spire Mountains and it took the ecological niece of the orcs.
And so the orcs moved out of the mountains.
Right.
And well, you know, this area has been attacked by orcs many times.
You may have heard the Phandalin and the...
So, what I understand is, in order to save this region, we have to help the orcs.
Is that what you're telling me?
No, no, that's not what I'm telling you.
It gets more complex.
That's good.
I really appreciate your willingness to see beyond the stereotypical impressions of orcs that permeate the local literature in Waterdeep.
And this shows you are a man of talent and the arts.
You are not.
No, I was just being an asshole.
He does that.
Xanth does not notice that.
He turns to you and says, the rest of you should take the rest of you are honored to be surrounded by somebody like Xanth, to be working with somebody like Vukradin, a man of such wide appreciation.
Anyway, anyways, so what happened is the orcs moved south.
And then he repeats the story that you knew that the orcs moved south and they split into three.
And then the Talosian orcs, the Talosian Anthro and took control of one faction of orcs, and then there's another faction of an orcs that still stayed loyal to the original tribe.
And basically, the orcs have now fractured into multiple groups.
And that the challenge is that you can't dealing with the dragon is.
And so like the dragon was just yet another mess in the area.
And then unfortunately, over the past little bit, the orcs have been able to capture more and more of the area around the Neverwinter Woods.
They've been driving people closer and closer to Phandalin.
This whole campaign is just everybody getting kicked out of home.
We're going to do a lot to get my music studio.
We're going to have to kill a dragon and a lot of orcs.
He was.
Why?
The dragon has a court.
Yeah, but that's not his goal.
He didn't.
He didn't earn that.
He pauses.
He goes, Soma, the little one, does he not understand the one with feathers?
Doesn't he understand these things?
I mean, he's different.
We're all a little different.
And then he turns, of course, to Valphine.
She's different too.
She's not evil.
She still looks at you.
You are a cleric of Lathader?
Yes.
You know that light is bad for Drau, yes.
Light is deliciously painful for me.
We're literally in the light right now.
It's a little bit towards the nighttime series.
Okay.
He looks at you.
Well, they make them all kinds.
You know, this one wants to help the orcs, the other is a drought.
Oh, what's that?
He stares at your staff.
This?
Yes.
You have Meryl's staff?
I do.
It's just an old stick he left in my house.
No, no, this is not Meryl's.
This is not a simple stuff.
This is a powerful staff.
It got a leaf the other day.
Oh, yes, I was looking at it.
It used to have more leaves and thingies, but it's one little leaf.
Meryl must know you.
I will help you, Soma.
Soma, what do you want?
Meryl and I were old friends.
I don't know.
We're just kind of trying to keep the world a safer place right now, trying to make sure everybody's got a place to live, trying to keep peace among the land.
Good, Soma.
Look, I don't know what's going on here.
The Emerald Enclave's gone a little bit nuts all.
Yeah, yeah.
There's idiots who are saying one thing, idiots who are saying the other thing.
The orcs are going around.
They can't decide whether the orcs are an intervention or naturalist.
They're accusing each other of everything.
Yeah, they can't even agree on terms.
Yes, when they argue about whether this is natural or this is intervention, tell me about it.
Orcs burn and pillage atrocate orcthalosians summon the evil god of storm, and this dragon is terrorizing everyone.
Yep, that sounds about right.
They're making no sense to me.
Exactly.
You must go deal with a dragon.
I think that is the most important thing.
Should we deal with the enclave as well?
We'll get to them.
But where can we find a dragon?
I mean, I know in the mountains, but where?
Well, he looks at Kaella, kicks her.
This one knows.
Oh, her?
She's a traitor.
Oh.
He stops.
He goes, Valphine, you are a drow, yes.
Yes.
You understand the importance of gray.
Gray.
Good.
Darkness and light.
That's what we're about.
Yes, yes.
And you can't have darkness with light.
What?
You can't have the darkness without the light.
You know, if there's no darkness, how do you know there's light?
Okay, let's not spend too much time theorizing about this.
What is the sound of one hand clapping?
All of a sudden, Valphine goes into like exaggeration.
Disassociates from her body.
No, what I tried to say is Valphine.
Can you tell us who is Sister Kaella?
She really worked for her.
Like, tell us what you know about her.
Oh, well, this is complicated.
So, as you know, after the War of the Dragons and the Giants, this place was kind of chaotic.
I was having a good time.
Life was grand.
And then the orcs started to move in.
And then this new gang of criminals comes in.
Right?
And there were three.
There was this one that they called the carver that nobody ever saw.
Yeah, we're still kind of looking for him.
And then, but he had three lieutenants.
He had this Borg person whom I think you killed.
How'd you know that?
I live in the forest.
I have many friends.
Just because you don't live in the forest doesn't mean you don't know things.
You know, Vukradin, the animals talk a lot.
Soma, thank you.
Yes.
These city dwellers, they think, oh, no, there's nobody here.
There's like animals, there's leaves, there's some birds, there's everything.
The animals are very chatty.
And the org, yeah.
And then there was Sister Kaella and Zax.
Yeah.
Two out of three are dead.
This one, why shouldn't we kill her?
She could lead us to the Carver.
Yeah.
Maybe.
He goes, well, he goes, why shouldn't you kill her?
I didn't say you shouldn't kill her.
I said you should get the information.
Then if you kill her, I have no problem.
Oh, you can kill her first and just you speak with Ted.
She may not talk.
So I rolled a 15-medicine, which is the tendency to use.
So she's now conscious with one hit point.
Hello, Sister Kaella.
Are you going to do the interrogation?
We have the face for a reason.
Yeah, but I don't like her.
This puts us in a difficult spot.
So, are we doing good cop bad cop here?
And says that the drow is the good cop, or is he a psychotically evil cop that's tried to remember all the different wants to kill her, so he's a bad cop.
Are you being the psychotically evil drow who's like, says, I haven't really tortured anybody in a long time, yeah?
I've got this blindness spell in daylight.
Yeah, funny options here, submit her to the sacraments, right?
I mean, you know, this and you could heal, keep healing her for she could die and you can heal her.
I mean, you even have a revivify spell, if I'm not mistaken.
Oh, wow, that's dark.
I mean, she goes really well, oddly.
We can mold Earth to dig graves.
I mean, this could, you know, don't forget she did.
She is a daughter of Nature and Satora, which was specialized in enhanced interrogation techniques that even the Drow felt with interrogation techniques.
Wow.
How Orwellian didn't call that.
I'm calling it here out of respect for everybody's sensibilities.
Yes.
He's off to get his torture instrument.
He comes out with a cat of nine tails and a gimp suit.
I'm leaving.
All right.
Okay.
So, so what's your so what's your setup?
Seriously.
She kind of looks at you and goes, Thank God you're alive.
Yes, you're the one who should be lucky if he's alive.
Oh, no, there was the other possibility.
No.
Yeah.
Jack swings, and I'm alive, and Jax is now going to torture me to death for several, you know, painfully long, protracted periods.
If you'd like.
Yes, but it's an if.
Whereas with Jax, it was a certainty.
So now, if I'd like to roll your intimidation with advantage.
This may not go well.
Okay, 16.
All right.
She is impressed with you.
Oh.
She's like, I didn't.
She pauses and goes, I didn't know you had it in you.
So now you need to take it.
You need to tell us more about this dragon or the carver swing.
He goes, the carver?
Oh, man.
The carver, he's like gone completely mad.
He's like, yeah.
And so he's like heading towards the dragon to possess it and wreak vengeance on everyone and everything.
Okay.
My audio just cut out again.
Would that be bad?
Like, who, like, who is he going to seek vengeance on?
Possibly us for knocking off Borg and others, right?
I mean, well, on a deeply personal level, me.
Right?
I mean, he's known for not exactly, you know.
I was kind of hoping that, you know, my plan wasn't to wait until there was the right moment to strike, but then you guys had to go grip the sword.
So you're telling me you were working against the carver the whole time.
Well, strictly speaking, after you killed the muscle and the carver accused me of not doing my work from an intelligence gathering perspective, I kind of thought that if the carver died, my life expectancy would increase.
Oh, why didn't you?
Why weren't you just upfront with us?
You had to do this whole secretive thing with Valphine.
Well, she was the only one who showed up.
I don't know.
Like, you guys, she was the one who showed up.
The rest of you didn't show up.
It's a long day.
And then she pauses.
And Vukradin, I had noticed that you had a difficulty in dealing with morally gray environments.
Yeah.
And so to be honest, I figured that a drow cleric of Lathander who understands the importance of darkness and light and all did really well in prison.
There are a lot of morally gray people there.
You can hang out with them for many years.
Everybody's innocent in prison.
She goes, as long as I'm alive, there's always hope.
Keep hoping, babe.
All right, hold on.
Let me get my.
All right.
So Sister Kaella.
So she goes, so, okay, so we were.
So she's like, yes, that was the sum total of it.
There wasn't anything else going on.
Do you know exactly where the dragon is?
Well, yes, he's in the Ice Spire Hold.
Okay.
Can you point that out to us on a map?
Yes.
Excellent.
She gives you directions to it.
She tells you where it is.
And what will you be doing?
What do you think you will be doing while we go and take care of this problem for you?
You want me to be in prison?
I'll go be in prison.
Yeah.
I want you in prison.
I'm cool with that.
I mean, you want me, do you want me to come with you?
I'm happy to come with you.
If you want me to.
That's there to the carver.
I mean, look, if the choices are, you know, if you want to put me in prison in Phandalin, I'm happy to be in prison in Phandalin.
In fact, if you wanted to put me in prison in Axelholm, that would even be better.
In where?
Axelholm?
Axholm.
Axelm.
That was where the dwarves were, which was the hideout the folks in Phandalin wanted.
Oh, right.
Yeah.
Right.
And like, if you wanted to put me there, I think that would be great.
In fact, if you were to go to Phandalin and tell everyone that they should go to Axholm and put me there with them, I think that would be.
Well, but she says, but there's a small problem with all of that.
What's that?
The small problem is that, unfortunately, the carvers also headed to Ice Spire Hold.
Right.
You told her.
Yeah, I think I told it to you.
And instead of us, you going there and instead of you listening to me, you tried to kill me.
And then it goes to Soma.
But you, Soma, you understood the value of life.
This is what I love.
This is what I love about you.
And Valphine, Valphine, we had an arrangement.
Yes, we have an arrangement.
Right.
And so I knew I could trust your arrangement and Soma's desire lack of interest.
Value of life.
You're like tied up or not right now, right?
She's very tied up.
Yeah.
That's why she's so cooperative.
Well, it looks like on the way to Icepire Hold is Phandalin.
So let's drop you off in jail and head off to the hold.
All right.
So she does.
Okay, let me just see who this is.
75.
All right.
She makes one last observation.
She says, I don't know what the carver is up to, and I don't know how he plans to take care of to handle the dragon, but you need to get there before the ritual is complete.
So loosely speaking, so just to make so that we don't have to do lots and lots and lots of physical math.
All right.
I'm just telling you how it is, and please don't start pulling out rulers and compasses.
Let's just go with the mechanics of this.
All right.
If you go to, if you can do, you can take one level of exhaustion and get to Icepire Hold.
55 miles.
Or.
No, but because you're going through mountains, uphills, right?
It's not like 55 miles.
It's 55 miles as the crows flies.
It's not exactly 50.
So you can take one level.
If you go through Phandalin, you take two levels of exhaustion to make it before the rain.
Make it in time.
Yes.
All right, let's see.
Now, if you can take zero levels of exhaustion, but then whether you arrive where you arrive in the ritual, I will roll dice and make decisions.
Decisions.
Hang on.
I got to look up exhaustion.
I vote us to take her with us and take the level.
Level one, disadvantage on ability checks.
Level two, speed is halved.
So we'd have disadvantage and half speed during the battle.
Unpleasant.
How can we cure exhaustion?
Hang on.
Lesser restoration cures.
I have lots of lesser restorations.
So we could use that.
Right.
But you would burn your spells.
You would burn your spells.
So that's your choice.
She does point out that, so she's cool with the other option.
Like, as long as she is, what she's not cool with is you guys running away.
The one thing she does say is like, you guys not going to Icepire Hold and not trying to handle the ritual, that would be bad.
You guys going to Icepire Hold and failing, and the dragon, you know, and Carver takes over the dragon and tries to kill everybody.
That would be also bad, but at least we tried.
And by we, I mean you.
Yeah.
Or we could just go to Neverwinter.
No, Phandalin.
We're high enough level we can go to Leylon now, right?
Yeah, we could go to Leylon.
You could do all of those.
Who's got the dragon slaying sword?
We should just go use it.
All of these are options.
Disadvantage on all ability checks.
Doesn't seem very good.
Can I do bird plants?
Yeah, I bet I can't.
And we got to drag her along.
Oh, no.
She's bound and gagged.
Hold on.
Santa said Santopoulos jumps in.
Vukradin didn't.
You've never asked if there is a third adoption.
Would you like to hear the third adoption?
Sure.
You got more options?
Yes.
We put her in the tomb.
And I see the WhatsApp mixer that nobody gets out.
I don't trust that.
He looks at you.
You don't trust me?
She has ways to get past your defenses.
I have another idea.
What?
Can the centaurs take us to Icespire?
Or the Elite.
They're talking about eagles.
Yeah.
You can.
There's four of you.
How many centaurs are there?
Only one.
Let's see how persuasive I am.
No, I mean, there's literally only one.
Well, I mean, one right here right now.
But you should come with him.
Fetch some friends.
And 17 persuasion.
He listens to you and goes, well, I think what I could do, I'm not going up into the mountains.
He looks at his feet.
My feet have not four of those things.
Plus, I do not do mountains.
I do fields and the forests.
I will get you to.
And he points you halfway here.
From there, you can go on your own.
He's taking us where?
To the gold mine or something?
Right, like somewhere around here.
Somewhere around the gold mine.
Yes.
That would obviate the round of exhaustion.
We can't take it.
One level's worth of exhaustion from the two options.
Yeah.
So you can take you to Phandalin and you can go to Icespire.
I'm just drawing the miles, like 35, 35.
Yeah.
Do we need anything else in Phandalin?
Do we need supplies?
Do we need allies?
Nah.
It's just one dragon, right?
We have a dragon slaying sword.
And I'm the naive one.
Hold on, hold on.
Hold on.
Just, you know, just roll an insight check.
Roll an insight check.
Yes.
That I can do.
No, no, I meant Dave.
Vukradin needs to roll the inside check.
Not good.
No, no, Vukradin didn't.
You do have a, as you're thinking about it, you do remember that the last time your position as mayor was hinged on your ability to demonstrate power over the dragon.
Yeah.
And then I saved the town from the dragon.
You know, and if you showed up and said I need help to fight the dragon, that might ruin your political, that might create opportunities for your political opponents.
I have opponents?
For a moment, the insight, you have the insight.
It passes.
You rolled very poorly, so I just threw that out there.
I'm not trying to convince you.
Hold on, guys.
I need to get something to drink.
Give me a second.
We can take Kaella, but she's got to stay in camp with Corbin watching her.
Yeah.
We'll have a thief watching the assassin.
It'll be great.
I mean, Corbin hasn't backstaged.
Go wrong.
He's been, you know, a non-starter.
We can also have Boney.
I don't know.
Yeah, what are we going to do with Boney?
I mean, he's coming with us, right?
Like, he's.
Well, I mean, Bony can help us travel faster.
Well, one of us.
So wait, wait, wait, wait.
So if I'm an animal, like a spider or something, and we have somebody riding the centaur, we only need two people.
Wait, wait, wait.
No, Gary, you can ride me as a bear.
You can put one on the centaur and one on Boney.
There you go.
Bear with the mouse.
We have three mountains.
We have a passenger centaur with passenger.
Yeah.
That should help.
No, we forgot about Brewbarry.
Hold on.
No, that's by the way.
You have two horses.
You have Boney.
Yeah.
Bony.
And we can have me.
We have Boney.
We have Xanth the Centaur.
And we have the Bear.
We have Soma the Bear, and somebody can ride Soma.
Yeah.
What are your classes?
You got you're an SMR, right, David?
Yeah.
Drows.
So you're medium.
So, yeah, the Centaur can carry both of you.
You're not wearing heavy armor, are you?
No.
I'm wearing somewhat heavy armor.
I mean, but you're not both wearing like full plate.
Sadly, no.
That would increase our AAC quite a bit.
Yes.
Well, I assume we have armor.
Yeah, exactly.
I just have it built into me.
She can carry 600 people, 600 pounds, according to 600 people.
So we decided that Corbin will be in charge of keeping for Kaella bound and gagged and near unconsciousness.
Not unconscious, but near unconsciousness.
Corbin says, That will be my pleasure.
She's allowed to have one hit point.
He goes, Yes, can I beat her until she has one hit point?
You roll, one of you roll an insight check.
Oh, they didn't like each other.
25.
Oh, dude, Valphine.
Valphine smiles.
She knows what's going on here.
She remembers the first time she got her hands on somebody who had hurt her.
Right, because they didn't get along, the two of them, right?
You don't know.
You're going to have to ask.
I know.
Let'll be a surprise.
I know enough.
I mean, you don't.
You both work for the same guy.
She was a big wig.
He was an outcast.
You want her to suffer anyway?
No, no.
Even if you knew you'd be okay with it.
What?
You just walk away.
Some things.
I'm going to focus on the music studio, killing a dragon, returning all this treasure to its rightful owners.
I got a lot going on right now.
I like how your coat of honor is just about loot.
You know, I have to kill him now.
When Sister Kaella realizes what your plan is, she starts screaming and cursing at you about leaving her with this lunatic and this madman.
Not a lunatic.
He's a friend.
He was part of your crew.
I'm sure the two of you will get a long period.
Yeah, he worked for the carver at one point.
Yeah.
You guys are teaching him some of our.
I've been teaching him some of our sacraments.
Sacrament.
Okay.
And with that, we will move that to the side.
Bad things happen over here.
Sacrament.
All right.
So Icespire Hold.
Icespire Hold.
All right.
Okie dokie.
So we can't do a full mount to avoid exhaustion.
What?
Can't do a full mounted approach.
No, we are avoiding exhaustion.
I'm saying if you had to go from here, you have to complete the full 55 miles, right?
Yeah.
Through the mountains, that was going to be one level of exhaustion.
But if you go to 35 miles on the
Horseback and then have to climb 20 miles.
That's a lot of climbing for adventurers, but it's well within your not exhaustion budget.
55 miles is in the exhaustion budget.
I mean, adventurers apparently can do 100-mile races like it's going out of style if you read the fifth edition.
Well, how much encumbrance do they have in these races?
And then monks, of course, can do 800 miles because monks can do that sort of thing.
Yes, I definitely had an encounter with a monk where I put all the bad guy in like this very far place, and then the monk just covered the entire distance in one round.
And I'm like, huh, this is why gyms hate monks.
Well, we can have one next adventure.
What?
I don't, I don't, I don't.
I said why they hate them.
I rolled with it.
Point is to have fun, not to win the encounter.
All right.
Okay.
Let's see.
I have a whole bunch of stuff written down.
Uh-oh.
I'm surprised you.
We are for this strongly, my friends.
We are long rested.
Everybody, long rest.
Long rest.
All right.
Clear all the.
I guess I'm not bear anymore.
Do we get bardic inspiration at any point?
Well, it only lasts for an hour, so I haven't given it to you yet, but it is on my list of things to do.
Kaella is at one hit point.
Yep, that looks right.
Every time she wakes up from her long rest, we reduce her damage.
Harbin pokes her in the eye a few times where she deserves to be.
And since she's Sister Kaella, she'll fit right in with the church.
I'm basically thinking we're going to be dealing with a Greek.
Now you'll have a branch in prison, Gary.
You'll have a temple and you'll have your prison branch.
It'll be great.
Yeah.
Thanks for looking up for Lothander.
Right.
Let me just go through this.
Okay.
See.
All right.
Okay.
So you arrive at the so you as you approach the mountain, you Soma, you get a natural sense that something is very off, that the natural order of things has been disrupted.
In this immediate vicinity of the mountain.
Yes.
And you see a right.
Who did this?
There you go.
Nature of four.
Yeah, you found some grass.
All right.
I didn't mean to do that.
I missed quite ignored.
Oh, that was you.
Sorry, I have advantage on nature checks.
Right.
Probably not going to beat Vukradin.
No, I didn't beat him.
Love it.
All right.
Okay.
So you.
So let's see where we're.
Okay.
So.
All right.
I see where I did.
Okay.
I need, sorry.
I spent quite a bit of time trying to figure this all out.
All right.
Okay.
Sorry.
Excuse me.
While I figured this all out.
All right.
As you approach the narrow defile, you see.
Okay, so this, where is this one?
Okay.
You see a perfectly, as you approach the mountains, you see the carver has less disturbing.
Your look at the trail that he's followed is very disturbing.
It's like he's following a straight line.
It's like if there's a rock, he goes over it.
He doesn't go around it.
Looney's in style.
He's flying, guys.
He's flying.
No, he's walking.
That's what's disturbing.
And so, so your question, so you also see, and so that's sort of like the first thing.
If you want to, you can go look at the footprints.
You can go on a bit of a clock to get to it before he gets the ritual, right?
Right.
So, do you want to just, I mean, you can take a turn around to just take a look.
I mean, I'm just six seconds.
All right.
We can take six seconds looking at the footprints.
As you look at them, the footprints, there's like a perfect rhythm to them.
Like a robotic robotic.
Like, you know, normal humans.
You're saying they would attract the worm.
No, as the construct, not by a guy who's under some sort of like demonic spell or something, like who's possessed.
Right.
So they're that, yeah, it doesn't, they don't look natural.
But the imprints themselves are human.
It could be an animal under a geez.
Yeah, that's possible.
Are they so?
They don't look natural, but are they like human footprints?
We don't really know what race the Carver is, right?
Like, yes, they're human.
You know, he's human.
Oh, we do know he's human?
Okay, for some reason, yeah.
If I didn't tell you, I should have already told you.
So then, so then it seems like he is like on a quest.
And Sister Kaella has seen him, right?
Yes.
Yeah, she's seen him.
Okay.
I mean, he could have been orc or something.
That's all.
All right.
Do you start up climbing?
I mean, we've got to get there before he takes over the dragon in the world, right?
Yep.
Yeah.
As you approach.
He's possessed.
Maybe we can make a deal with the dragon.
Deal with the dragon?
They're quite intelligent.
Assassins, yes.
Dragons now.
If you get their phylactery.
What are you up against dragons now?
Right.
Okay.
So you start climbing.
You start climbing, I presume, right?
You're going to follow his path, or are you going to try to directly, or how are you going to do it?
Follow his path.
That's where we're heading.
Is this particularly difficult for everyone?
The dragon's not as big of a threat as he is.
I scout ahead in spider form or something like that.
I mean, if the climb is arduous, right?
Like that gives me something like 40 or 50 foot climb.
No, I'm just sorry.
Okay.
So you have to like, as you're doing this, someone has to roll a wisdom survival check to navigate the treacherous mountain paths while following the unnatural trail.
Who does that?
There's going to be a bunch of checks.
Apparently, I got a 20.
Okay, there's going to be six checks.
So there's going to be a wisdom, strength, wisdom, intelligence, and dexterity.
You want to get three out of the six positives.
So just I got a survival.
All right.
So all right.
Someone else has to do athletics, perception, nature, or stealth.
Brewbarry should do athletics.
Brewbarry fits to athletics.
All right.
I'll do the nature.
Nature.
Well done, Brewbarry.
Brewbarry.
Nature 12.
Okay.
What else we got?
That was three.
All right.
Perception.
What?
Perception?
That sounds scary.
Nice.
What did you do?
23.
All right.
So I think that's three.
So as you climb up, as you follow the trail, you approach a narrow defilé.
Oh, what?
Narrow defilé.
Oh.
Defile?
Defile.
That's the word I'm looking for.
Narrow pass.
Narrow pass or gorge between mountains or hills.
I know it in the French.
I don't know it in English.
You do know.
Okay.
So what is it in English?
Pronounce it?
Defile.
Really?
Like, defile?
That's why it always awkwarded me out.
I was like, is it really pronounced the same thing?
We steal.
Words all the time.
Don't worry about it.
No, I'm not worried about it.
I'm just like.
Colonize all the languages.
Because every word in English is.
Defile is a verb, not a noun, so I'm very confused.
Defile.
That's a defile, apparently.
Yeah, that's a verb.
Oh, okay.
Well, it's one of those words that I didn't know how there's something, but I don't.
It's not a word I'm using.
Hold on.
And it is exactly of French origin.
Yeah.
As you approach Narrow Defile, you see the Carver's Trail cuts through the center.
As you look around, you notice stone giants gathered around the path, murmuring in their deep language.
One giant points at the unnatural line in the head, snow, and shakes its head slowly.
What, there are giants here?
Yes, they're stone giants.
They're very not talkative.
But they're talking constantly in their language.
Yes, I mean, they're a noun and their language, which Brewbarry and Valphine both speak.
Oh, wow.
All right.
So they're murmuring in their deep language, and they are talking about the stones and the rocks, and how the stones and the rocks are off, and that something is off.
Brewbarry should ask, have you seen our prey?
Well, no, no, no.
Can we talk to the giants?
Well, Brewbarry asks that, and they point to the, they said that they say the little one with the obsidian sword came through this path.
And then as he came.
Did you try to stop him?
He is a little one.
He is of no concern of ours.
I wouldn't be so sure.
Is there a way we can help you?
Is there a way you can help us?
They look at you and go, and he points to the he points to the path, indicating that the way you could help him is by dealing with the other little one.
I thought he was of no concern.
He is of no concern to them.
To us.
So how would us dealing with him help you?
He would no longer be here and not talking to us.
You can help us by geeing the TFO.
Roll a nature check, Dave.
Okay.
Control nature check.
15.
You do remember something about stone giants being like these colossal introverts of giant kind.
Introverts?
Yes.
They hate like when people they kind of like their view of the universe is there's a rock.
It's too talkative.
Okay.
So this is not them.
This is who they are.
They don't like talking.
They don't like noise.
They don't like movement.
They don't like the dragon.
They don't.
The dragon doesn't bother them.
Well, you can ask.
Yeah, I'd like to ask them about the dragon.
He goes, yes, the dragon.
There's a sigh.
When Am broke the sundering, some thought that it was time for giants to seize power over the little ones.
Those giants failed.
And they were tempted by, and Aum was tempted by the power of Tiamat and her plans to rule the world with her dragons.
We have learnt from Hecaton that now the war with the dragons is over and the war with the little ones is over.
The dragon fighting dragons.
Yes, the dragon can stay where the dragon lives and the dragon does not bother us.
He will soon.
I'm telling you what they think.
Yeah, I'm telling them what to think.
All right.
The corrupted one seeks to corrupt the dragon.
I'm sorry, could you repeat what you said?
The corrupt.
One seeks to corrupt the dragon.
Yeah.
Do you have any proof?
Can we give him, you know, the one HP Layla or Sister Kaella?
She's not proof either.
She's not there.
Oh, right.
And she's not.
Hold on.
Hold on, hold on, hold on.
But there's something that he said that got you thinking.
that that triggered you and he said something is wrong with the rocks the uh the wand you have that wand of like detect unnatural things i mean we know things are unnatural i guess i can throw it down the the staff has the detect unnatural so burn that charge but i mean we know it's unnatural i don't think it tells you you know it's unnatural but you now know you have a particular staff that's noted in this area of the world uh oh because the centaur knew about it right all right all right touch the staff to some of the uh out-of-place rocks what do we get um they are they are rocks that have been warped that some kind of psychic energy has warped reality to find a warped rock here instead of like looking like a rock it looks like a rock that's continuously shimmering like phasing in and out or something yes phasing in and out and when you tweet we don't just see that like by staring at the rocks um no it's when you turn on the magic when you when you when the without the magic what it looks like to an outside observer is the rock just moves around a little bit like it appears as if the rock's just rolling with no wind but what's really going on is it's shifting in phase and that's causing it to become unbalanced are they headed in any consistent direction or anything no but what you do notice is that they're primarily where the carver has walked yeah that makes sense i mean there's that guy is possessed there's nobody walks like that um what he's possessed by i don't know right the stone giants look at you and they say hmm they say well this is again Katon has said and the failure of the the breaking of the sundering has shown that giants must take care of giant things but he decides to give you a potion nonetheless and it's not blood what is it what's no it's not blood money i know um potion of greater healing uh something for giant strength what that would have been my favorite okay no i'm teasing him false i i no actually i was trying to give you something that useful potion of giant strength is also fine like would you prefer that no no no no i'm being silly uh what's Brewbarry's strength oh god his strength is 18 18 even when he's raging yeah and uh potion of stone giant strength what is that 24 oh no you weren't you're not getting one of those potion of hill giant strength is what you're getting hill giant he's not giving no he's not making some potion out of dead stone giant toenailed that's only that's only uh right i mean just one strength that only gives him a plus one yeah yeah yeah the healing's probably better yeah what do you think is stone giant's gonna hand you like some potion made from dead stone giant parts well he could give us cloud giant strength how's that they're higher in the ordinal i know yeah well you know that that would violate the rules of the ordinal all everybody does is violate the rules it's true and when he says that he goes and this is why we had the war of the giants and so many giants died and so many little people died and um had to learn and and and you know he you start hearing this it like if it was possible for you to get any more board from a sermon all right that's what back to the height guys we gotta go up up up all right following the track forward upward upward not forward oh can i ask the giants one more thing yes was there anybody else with the little one no excellent obsidian sword though do we know anything about that like not the giants else obsidian sword i know that i don't want to come anywhere near it that's why a pole person level draining sword all right
Okay, you now approach this ice, so you get past the stone giant's pass.
All right, you arrive at what is going to be known as the glacier of whispers.
The ice here is stained with violet and violet, the color violet energy.
Frozen faces press against the ice from within, their mouths moving in silent screams.
The carver's footprints glow with faint psychic energy, and you hear whispers in your mind: He walks without rest, without breath, without soul.
All right, so to get through this, we're gonna either have to all right, you have to pass a couple of skill checks.
Um, wisdom, strength, wisdom, intelligence, or dexterity, navigate the treacherous mountain paths, climb sheer walls.
Uh, so yeah, navigate, either navigate and spot hidden dart.
So, it's either survival to navigate the treacherous mountain paths, perception, spot hidden dangers like thin ice or avalanche risks.
Is this a place to bardically inspire us to?
22 perception.
All right, so you successfully navigated the first, and what was the other one?
Did you do the nature Ukraine, or is it going to be Soma?
Soma did nature, right?
Ah, I haven't.
I mean, I have advantage on nature in nature, so yeah, let me go for go through your nature.
Yeah, where the heck did I leave my character sheet?
There it is 14.
All right, um, so there's one success and one failure.
Oh, what else?
What else you got?
Uh, that's all the only choices, but that's okay.
Oh, I thought there was like a dexterity warning.
No, no, I'm that was me.
I misspoke.
I'm sorry, I misspoke.
Um, there's just two checks, yeah, there are two checks.
All right, all right, okay, and now you must all wear as you're going through this.
The psychic resonance starts to affect you and uh more and starts to affect you.
Um, so roll a group wisdom save, okay.
Pretty good saves.
Everybody's on 15.
Just as you're okay, well, that's good.
Just as you figure, um, just as you're about to do that, Valphine notices that she can pray for Lothander's blessing to grant saves and against psychic effects for 10 minutes.
This is just some new thing that I can do.
No, you remember something about how your local priestly clerics had told you that this about this area, that Lathander particularly you didn't pay that much attention to it.
You figured it was all nonsense.
So, I could pray him to do what again for this particular location.
I just remember reading it in my notes.
It doesn't matter since you guys passed it.
But if you hadn't passed it, you could have used that to get everybody to give an advantage.
All right.
Oh, on the navigating through the day.
On psychic stuff, yeah.
On the psychic stuff.
All right.
You managed to navigate through that.
And now we approach the final area before you approach the top of the climbing mountains.
And that says, you find the frozen corpses of young white Drake, its eyes burned out with necrotic energy.
The carver didn't bother to go around.
He walks straight through the creature's lair.
Their mother Drake circles above, confused and enraged by the violation of her territory.
So before you, let me just see, you have some advantages here.
Okay.
Well, one thing you could do, Vukradin, is it comes to you that you can play some music to calm the agitated Drake.
Right.
A little Pied Piper scenario going on.
What is a Drake?
Baby dragon?
Yeah, a Drake is a kind of drag.
It's an adolescent.
What did you roll?
The music.
Has the desired effect.
I bet you bless.
So, yes, so as you as you manage to, as you play the music, the mother dragons.
Does anybody else join in?
Is there just Vukradin and I assume Brewbarry would have joined in, right?
He loves this shit.
No, we're not going for the death metal kind of stuff.
We're trying to calm him down a little bit.
We'll just do some moonlight sonata here.
The death metal alibi.
What did we call it?
The Lathandrian mix of Lathandrian mix.
Like, we had a whole genre of music for this.
Lathander is death chat.
Yeah, death chat.
Yeah.
All right.
The Drake, the mother Drake calms down and lies down next to her dead in size.
If you make a break for it, you could probably get past her without having to have a foot.
I feel bad for her.
We don't need to fight her.
Okay.
So you keep playing the Pied Piper and run away.
Is that what I'm hearing?
For sure.
Yeah.
All right.
Save it for the real guy.
Or Mother Drake.
Okay.
Mother's Real.
It's one of your kids that got, you know, Mother's or Resilience.
We are.
All right.
Unfortunately, the path now leads through some impossible terrain, which will require you to come up with some creative solutions to it.
Obviously.
All right.
Get going, guys.
Mold Earth.
I've got Mold Earth.
I've got to turn this impassable terrain into passable terrain.
Five feet at a time.
Yeah.
Six seconds works on stone.
Okay.
So this, okay, fair.
So the problem with it is that there's these boulders.
I mean, it's a mountain.
It's a mountain with peaks and ice.
But there's just enough dirt for you to manipulate things.
Exactly.
But you're going to have to roll to see if you manipulate it successfully or create an even bigger mess like an album.
Oh, I like this one.
Yeah, let's do this.
Who's rolling?
I'm not going to cast it.
I was the caster.
Yeah, so it seems like it'd be me.
I'm trying to think what it would be.
Like, I have to check this.
Arcana?
Tetris?
No.
Survival?
Yeah.
All right.
So rather than me telling you what it is, tell me what you want, which one of your many different ways you're planning to do it and explain how that is justified by the ability check you want to use.
Let's use Soma.
Geez.
I'm trying to look at what would actually be like a thing that I guess survival because it's like building out.
Basically, I'm trying to carve a structure out of it.
So use Mold Earth to pull things around to move the stones aside and move it, you know, into like.
Sold.
I think that's a great one.
Roll the survival check DC15.
And I gave you Bardic inspiration.
Well, I don't need it.
I got a ton of things.
Okay.
Well, you still will record it on your sheet anyway.
Yeah.
All right.
Oh, sure.
I'll be bardically inspired.
Yes.
And it's 10.30, so we will stop here.
All right.
See you guys.
Gary.
No, it's not next week, the week after.
You said you're probably not out, right?
Or not around, right?
Yeah.
See you guys next week then, huh?
Yeah, next week's fine.
Thanks.
Thank you guys.
I like the novel use of Mold Earth there.
Yeah, I was just trying to carve out a little bit.
Finally, a use for Mold Earth.
There's always a useful Mold Earth.
You've used Mold Earth before.
It saved your character.
Yeah, that's right.
When you guys got stuck in that trap in the collapse, the bank or whatever.
Yes.
Which, by the way, for a fifth edition module, to have a trap that could be a TPK if the party walks in the wrong way in an introductory module is really weird.
How could it be a TPK?
Well, I didn't run it that way, but if we all walked in, we could have died.
If you all walk in, but the rules as written say is it collapses and you're all covered in dirt and you can't dig yourselves out.
Oh, we're all suffocating.
Yeah, I'm like, I haven't seen a trap like that since I read first edition module.
Tomb of Horrors.
Yeah.
I of course did not like that at all.
And so I said, okay, whoever's at the very end can save the party.
But like, it, it was just a very odd sort of like, should I don't like traps like that because I think they're, if I wanted to play that, we could play first edition.
And you could have a stack of characters.
Yeah.
We never did finish Tomb of Annihilation.
All right.
It was fun.
All right, guys.
Bye-bye.